# 哈喽大家好
Hello everyone
# 最近收到很多私信
We got a lot of PMs recently
# 有很多同学说要想看分解猪肉
Many people say that they are interested in how pork cuts are divided
# 今天我就跟四伯一起
So today, together with uncle
# 弄了一头猪过来跟大家分享
we grabbed a pig to share with you
# 哪些部位该怎么做（烹饪）然后
how to cook each different cut, and...
# 还有很多（猪的）部位大家不知道叫什么名字
And many people have no idea how each cut is named
# 不知道购买的时候有什么小技巧
or what the tips are for buying pork
# 本期视频就跟大家分享这些小技巧
So in this video, I'll share the tips with you
# 四伯爷回来啦
Welcome back, uncle
# 这个猪有多重
How heavy is the pig?
# 差不多活猪有200斤左右
It was almost 200 jin when alive (jin = 500g)
# 活的有200斤那现在呢
Oh, 200 jin when alive. How about now?
# 现在有150斤到160斤左右。
Now it should be 150 to 160 jin
# 我试一下
Let me try
# 我们两爷子来试哈看嘛
Yeah, let us two have a try
# 挂到那个看
Hang it over there
# 拖一哈下来就下来了
Drag it down. That's how we move it
# 不重
Not heavy # light weight baby!
# 1 2 3
1 2 3
# 150多斤这头猪
This pig weighs over 150 jin
# 是它的肉有150多斤
I mean, its meat weighs over 150 jin
# 是去掉了内脏呀乱七八糟的东西的所有的东西
after removing the organs and those kinds of things
# 然后我们今甜用这条猪
And today, we'll use this pig
# 做一个解刨
for an anatomy
# 也不算是解刨及时把它每个部位弄出来
Not actually anatomy. Just divide each part of it
# 就是
which is
# 由我伯爷来跟你们分享
Uncle will share with you
# 怎么样子来解刨这些猪肉怎么买这些猪肉
How to divide different cuts of pork, and how to buy
# 我来跟你们分享这个猪肉该怎么做
I'll share with you how to cook
# 怎么样子做才更好吃
and what are the good recipes for them
# 现在我四伯要 准备把这个猪头下（卸）下来
Now uncle is about to take of this pork head
# 我们做菜的里面的话猪头只适合用来卤
Speaking of cooking, pork head is only good for a master stock dish
# 很少用来做其它的
We basically don't use it for other dishes
# 要嘛就是把它头里面的肉弄出来做拆骨肉
Or we take out the meat out, into boneless meat
# 很出名的一道湘菜
There is a very famous Hunan cuisine
# 叫做小炒拆骨肉
called "Xiaochao Chaigurou" ("stir-fried boneless pork")
# 就是猪头里面的肉
which is meat from pork head
# 其实我们这个猪脸猪耳朵弄来做凉菜
The pork face and ears can be made into a salad
# 做凉菜
Yeah, salad
# 好吧 我们现在开始第一步
Alright, now let's get started
# 下猪头
Taking off the pork head
# 先下耳朵
We cut off the ear first?
# 哦
Oh...
# 我以为你先下耳朵
Thought you are going to cut off the ear
# 一哈就弄下来了
You made it instantly
# 那还用说
Any questions?
# 这一个部位就适合用来做肘子
This part is good for a knuckle dish # 视频里比划的部位似乎是上臂，请检查
# 很出名的一道菜东坡肘子
There's a famous dish, Dongpo Pork Knuckle
# 然后这个蹄子的话适合用来炖汤
And the trotter is very good for soup stock
# 要车圆不是别人看斗扁塌塌的
Must cut it round. Or it looks flat
# 现在我四伯要用这个来敲一下
Now, uncle is going to cleave it
# 哦哟
Whoa
# 它这个骨头一敲就断了
The bone breaks as you cleave it
# 好
Alright
# 这是第一支前腿
This is the first front leg
# 好
Good
# 这个后腿的话呢
Speaking of a rear leg
# 这个骨头就比较多
Too much bone
# 后腿的骨头比较多就更适合用弄来炖汤
As there is much bone, it's better for a soup stock
# 或者是用来卤
Or a master stock
# 它就不适合做什么肘子了
Not good for knuckle dishes
# 因为你看肉少骨头多
Because, as you see, less meat than bones
# 现在我跟大家分享一下
Now I'll share with you
# 我们之前做的回锅肉说的二刀肉在哪里
Where is the "Er Dao Rou" ("second cut pork") we mentioned before for double-cooked pork
# 二刀肉在这个位置
This is where "Er Dao Rou" is
# 在这个位置
Right here
# 是不是 嗯嗯嗯
- Is that correct?
- Yeah
# 在这个位置
Right here
# 里脊的话
Speaking of tenderloin
# 从这个地方一直上来一直上来
From here, and goes all the way up
# 这是它的外里脊
This is the "outer loin"
# 两边有两条这么粗的
One thick strip at each side
# 大概这么粗
About this thick
# 这个是它的里脊
This is the tenderloin
# 应该有这么长嘛
Should be this long
# 现在我们把这个边口砍开
Now let's divide it into "Bian Kou" (pig halves)
# 四伯的刀法特别准
Uncle has accurate knife skills
# 每一刀都砍在它的想砍到的地方
He always cleaves at where he wants to
# 咦 这样砍边口还要得
Eh, this is not bad for dividing a pig into halves
# 现在我们取腰子要先把这个边油取下来
Before taking off the kidneys, let's first take off the "Bian You" ("side fat")
# 这个边油就是我们农村买这个一坨一坨的买回来熬猪油的地方
This is the part we buy to extract lard in countryside
# 这个边油我四伯用一只手就把它扯下来了
Now uncle single-handedly teared off the fatback
# 少得很嘎
Very little?
# 这个猪瘦都嘛
This pig was slim
# 这个猪妖的话是在这个边油里面
The kidneys are hiding in the "Bian You"
# 现在这个猪妖是原始状态
Now the kidneys are still in the primitive status
# 一般大家买到的猪腰
For those you can buy in the market
# 他都是把这个划开拿出来
they slice if open and take the kidneys out
# 为什么有些要割两刀呢
Why do some kidneys have slices on them?
# 割两刀是这个状态
This is how they are sliced
# 哦 不要他割烂了
Oh, not for dividing it
# 不是要把它割烂了
We slice it not for diving it
# 你看到没这个油的朦子
See? This fatty membrane
# 哦 他是为了把这个弄开
Oh, it's for opening the membrane
# 哦 主要是把油这个朦子撕开
It's mostly for tearing off the membrane
# 好光鲜哦 你看
Smooth, isn't it?
# 我们买猪腰最好的话就是买有点发白的
If you buy pork kidneys, it's best to buy those looking a little bit white
# 比如说有这里一坨红的那里一坨红的肯定是有问题的
In case there are red spots, there must be some issues
# 下一步我们取猪身上真正的里脊肉出来给大家看一下
Now, let's cut the real tenderloin for you
# 其实里脊肉一头猪就一点点
Actually, one pig has only a little tenderloin
# 它外面的一坨叫外里脊
The cut outside is called "Wai Liji" (outer loin)
# 外脊肉
"Outer loin"
# 这个是内脊肉
This is the "inner loin" (tenderloin)
# 里脊分内外
Yeah, there are outer and inner loins
# 可能这头200斤的猪
This pig weighed 200 jin (jin = 500g)
# 毛猪的话
when it was alive
# 就只有1斤多一点
but it has only about 1 jin tenderloin
# 其实这个确实是很难买的
So actually, it's really hard to buy pork tenderloin
# 现在我四伯在剃后面这个猪屁股肉
Now uncle is cutting the ham
# 俗称二刀肉
Also known as "Er Dao Rou" ("second cut pork")
# 这一块肉做回锅肉是最后吃的
which is the best cut for double-cooked pork
# 这一坨是它是棒子骨嘎
This is the femur bone?
# 这一坨就是棒骨
This is the femur bone
# 第一刀现在下的是第一刀
The first cut. This is still the first cut
# 第一刀不叫做二刀肉
The first cut is not the "Er Dao Rou"
# 什么叫二刀肉
Why is it called "Er Dao Rou"?
# 第二刀就是叫做二刀肉
Only the second cut counts as "Er Dao Rou"
# 这一刀就是二刀肉了
This cut will be "Er Dao Rou"
# 第二刀了啊
The second cut now
# 这一坨真正的二刀肉
The real "Er Dao Rou"
# 这一坨二刀肉的话
This "Er Dao Rou"...
# 最好的位置再什么位置
What's the best part of it?
# 在这个位置
It's right here
It's here
# 为什么这么说呢
Why do we say that?
# 因为它炒回锅肉不会掉
Because it doesn't break down when we cook a double-cooked pork
# 不会脱层
The layers don't detach
# 如果是下面这一部分的话
If we use the lower part
# 它炒出来肥的会跟瘦的会散开
the fat and lean parts may detach after cooking
# 这点就不好
which is not good
# 好 现在开始剃排骨
Alright, now let's cut out the ribs
# 排骨下完之后剩下的就是五花肉
After taking off the ribs, what remains is pork belly
# 我四伯现在把排骨下下来了
Now uncle has taken off the ribs
# 我跟大家看一下一整块完整的排骨是什么样的
Let me show you what the whole ribs of a pig looks like
# 其实你们在市场上面买的话
Actually, if you buy pork ribs in the market
# 排骨这边前面这个是没有的
you won't see the front part of the ribs
# 然后从这里后面是没有的
or the read part from here
# 这个地方剁掉
This part is chopped off
# 从这个地方剁掉
And this part is chopped off
# 然后这中间卖的超贵
And the middle part is super expensive
# 猪身上最贵的地方
The most expensive part of a pig
# 肉当中最贵的就应该是排骨了
Ribs should be the most expensive cut of pork
# 这一条就是外里脊了
This strip is the "outer loin"
# 这一条取下来之后
After removing this trip
# 这个位置就是五花肉 五花肉
- This part is pork belly
- Pork belly
# 我们做红烧肉
Red braised pork
# 基本上都是用这一块肉来做的
is mostly made from this part
# 红烧肉 扣肉
Red braised pork, "Kou Rou" pork
# 对 还有扣肉也基本上是用这块肉
Yeah, "Kou Rou" also uses this part
# 还有樱桃肉
And "Yingtao Rou" (with an accent)
# 樱桃肉我四伯说的就是樱桃肉
[Explaining uncle's accent]
# 好
Yeah
# 这一坨呢 我四伯是连着肥肉一起切下来的里脊肉
This chunk is the loin. Uncle cut it off together with fat
# 这一条才是真正的里脊
And this strip is the real tenderloin
# 这一条是外脊
This strip is the "outer loin"
# 他们悬殊的比较大
They are very different
# 重量悬殊比较大
Very different in weight
# 然后这一条无论你怎么炒
And no matter how you cook this strip
# 无论你腌制或者不腌制都很嫩
whether to marinate or not, it's always very tender
# 但是这一条
However, for this strip
# 若果越大条的话
The larger the strip goes
# 炒出来就会有一点老
the dish might be harder to chew
# 如果你不腌制不处理一下
If you didn't marinate or process it in advance
# 它就没有那么好吃
then it doesn't taste as good
# 这个肉的话
Now this chunk
# 用来炒
Good for stir fry
# 大家可以看到吗
Can you guys see it?
# 这后面还有一块板筋
There's a "Ban Jin" ("hard ligament") on it
# 这个板筋切下来
We can cut out the "Ban Jin"
# 还可以做成一个香辣板筋
and make a "Xiangla Banjin" spicy dish
# 干煸板筋
or a dry-fried dish
# 现在我四伯再处理这个前夹肉
Now uncle is handling the front shoulder # 请检查部位
# 把这个扇骨剔下来
Removing the shoulder blade
# 这一块为什么叫扇骨就是这个原因
Why do we call it the "fan bone" in Chinese?
# 像扇子
Looks like a fan
# 由我四伯来给大家讲解一下
Now uncle will explain to you
# 这个肉适合怎么吃
how should each part be cooked
# 然后最主要是现在当前的价格
and most importantly, what the current price is
# 来嘛 四伯
Come on, uncle
# 这个猪头可以剔下来搞腌腊
This pork head can be cured
# 也可以做凉菜 卤猪头
- And for salad
- Master stock
# 卤猪头
Yeah, master stock
# 好多钱斤
How much is it?
# 现在他们搞腌腊的收购9块钱1斤
Those meat curers buy it in bulk at 9 yuan/jin
# 是收购
That's in bulk
# 如果是在市场上面卖呢
How much is it in the market?
# 市场上面卖12块钱1斤
In the market, it's 12 yuan/jin
# 现在我们聊一下这个
Now let's talk about this
# 这个是前肘 刚才都说了
This is the front knuckle, as we said
# 嗯 这个前肘
Yeah, front knuckle
# 适合做东坡肘子
Good for Dongpo Pork Knuckle
# 做汤
And stew
# 多少钱1斤呢
How much is it?
# 26块钱1斤
26 yuan/jin
# 这个在市面上单买就是30块钱1斤
This is 30 yuan/jin in the market, when retailed
# 这个是猪舌头
This is the pork tongue
# 这个
This one
# 这个筒骨现在可以拿来煲汤
This femur bone can be used for a soup stock
# 这个市场价格上18-20块钱1斤目前
The current market price is 18-20 yuan/jin
# 现在这个前夹肉
The front shoulder
# 可以煎炒
can be stir fried
# 这个可以
This can be...
# 可以做白肉
used for "Bai Rou"
# 炒肉丝
Or stir fried juliennes
# 炒肉丝做白肉
Stir fried juliennes, and "Bai Rou"
# 这个肥肉可以拿来做条肉
This fat part can be used as "Tiao Rou"
# 可以用来榨油
For lard extraction
# 这个跟前夹肉一样的价
This is at the same price as front shoulder
# 但是这个单买要30块钱1斤
However, the retail price is 30 yuan/jin
# 单买
Retail
# 这个五花肉还是25块钱1斤
This pork belly is at 25 yuan/jin
# 25块
# 现在这个五花肉特别抢手
Now pork belly is popular
# 五花肉特别抢手现在
Pork belly gets really popular
# 还不好买
and also gets hard to buy
# 五花肉的用处很大
Pork belly has many uses
# 可以做烧白 夹沙肉
For example, "Shao Bai" or "Jia Sha Rou"
# 红烧肉
Red braised pork
# 可以做樱桃肉
and "Yingtao Rou"
# 这个排骨
And the ribs
# 两边要便宜一点点
The two ends are cheaper
# 两边便宜中间贵
Two ends are cheap, and the middle part is expensive
# 中间的大排很贵
The big ribs in the middle are expensive
# 大排骨
Big ribs
# 大排光是中间的
The big ribs, just those in the middle
# 可以买上30块钱1斤
can cost 30 yuan/jin
# 中间的30块钱1斤
30 yuan/jin in the middle
# 然后两边呢
How about the two ends?
# 两边的25-26块钱1斤
25-26 yuan/jin
# 25-26块钱1斤
25 or 26
# 这一坨我来跟大家介绍一下
Let me introduce this chunk
# 这一坨是真正的里脊肉
This chunk is the real tenderloin
# 这个多少钱一斤
How much is it?
# 这个要买32一斤
This costs 32 yuan/jin
# 32一斤
32 yuan/jin
# 相比要比这个贵几块钱1斤
A few yuan more expensive than that one
# 对对对
Yeah, yeah, yeah
# 而且还很难买
And also hard to buy
# 这个是后腿肉
This is the rear leg
# 后腿肉可以搞腌腊
Rear legs can be cured
# 可以煎炒但是没有前夹肉好吃
Can also be cooked, but not as good as front shoulder
# 这个煎起有点死板 没有前夹肉嫩
It's a bit dry after cooking. Less tender than front shoulder
# 就是这个肉稍微老一些
So this cut is a bit more dry
# 炒的话稍微老一些
Yeah, a bit dry after cooking
# 这个就是二刀肉
This is the "Er Dao Rou" ("second cut pork")
# 这个好多钱 这个现在跟前夹肉一样的25块钱1斤
- How much?
- This is the same as front shoulder, 25 yuan/jin
# 这个是二刀肉
This is "Er Dao Rou"
# 我们四川做回锅肉这一坨少不了
This is the essential part for double-cooked pork in Sichuan
# 它炒出来这个肉又嫩然后这个肥的又香
After cooking, the lean meat is tender, while the fat is aromatic
# 也可以做腌腊做腊肉
Can also be cured
# 多少钱1斤
How much is it?
# 这个就要贵1块钱1斤大概26块钱1斤
This is one yuan more expensive. About 26 yuan/jin
# 26块钱1斤
26 yuan/jin
# 这个腰子呢
How about the kidneys?
# 腰子我们以前卖5块钱1个
Kidneys... It used to be 5 yuan each
# 现在可以卖到26块钱1斤
Now it can be 26 yuan/jin
# 过称
Weighed
# 再下面这个是
The next one is
# 这个是板油
This is the fatback # 请检查这个和前面的“边油”是不是同一个
# 猪的板油
Pork fatback
# 这个现在前几天可以卖到28块钱1斤
This was at 28 yuan/jin a few days ago
# 现在只有24-25块钱1斤
Now it's at 24-25 yuan/jin
# 那个是猪腿的打屁肉
This is the "pork ass" in the leg
# 我们四川说的打屁肉就是屁股上面的那一坨肉
We call it "pork ass" in Sichuanese, which is the part at the back of the ass
# 就是屁股尖的臀尖肉
It's at the top of the ass, ass top
# 多少钱
How much?
# 还是25-26块钱1斤
Same, 25-26 yuan/jin
Still 25-26 yuan/jin
# 然后我们来聊一下这个后腿
Now let's talk about the rear leg
# 这个后脚就比前脚相因1块钱1斤
Rear legs are cheaper than front legs
# 它买26这个只买25块钱1斤
Front legs are at 26. This is only 25 yuan/jin
# 25块钱1斤 哦
25 yuan/jin
# 那这个呢
How about this?
# 这个就更贵了
This is more expensive
# 这个就是35块钱1斤
This is 35 yuan/jin
# 他们一般的人是买不到的
Regular people can't buy this
# 好啦本期视频我们就聊到这里
Alright, that's all for this video
# 关于猪肉的一些知识啊还有一些价格啊
We've talked about some knowledge about pork, and about the price
# 部位呀
And cuts
# 部位对 暂时到这里 好啦
Cuts, yeah. That's all, yeah
# 拜拜
Bye bye